<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fundamentals on Computer Networking</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/fundamentals/</link><description>Recent content in Fundamentals on Computer Networking</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/docs/fundamentals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Transmission</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/fundamentals/transmission/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/fundamentals/transmission/</guid><description>Transmission # Encoding # First of all, the physical layer transmits signals, not bits. So we need to translate back and forth. This is done via modulation and demodulation.
Clock recovery # Clock recovery means being able to recover and deduce the senders clock, since the sender sends information triggered by clock cycles.
Intuitively, clock recovery is easier by sending frequent 0-1 and 1-0 transmissions.
Scheme 1 - NRZ # The simplest scheme.</description></item><item><title>Switches, Links, &amp; Bridges</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/fundamentals/switches-links-bridges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/fundamentals/switches-links-bridges/</guid><description>Switches, Links, &amp;amp; Bridges # A switch is a specialized computer that
allows it to receive and send bits/frames that arrive over links. Links are physically connected to switches at attachment ports or switch ports (usually just called ports).
Networks built out of such components are usually just called receive and forward networks.
The fundamental idea of packet switching is to allow multiple flows of data over a single physical link, AKA multiplexing.</description></item><item><title>Ethernet</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/fundamentals/ethernet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/fundamentals/ethernet/</guid><description>Ethernet and Shared Media Access # And then when there are more than two computers trying to communicate over a medium (”link”), we have to deal with sharing.
This is the media access or channel access problem.
Protocols to solve this are called MAC (media access control) protocols.
There are centralized and decentralized MAC protocols.
Aloha # The Ethernet has its roots in an early packet radio network, called Aloha, developed at the University of Hawaii to support computer communication across the Hawaiian Islands.</description></item><item><title>Wireless</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/fundamentals/wireless/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/fundamentals/wireless/</guid><description> Wireless #</description></item></channel></rss>